▼ jlalucescareer123@gmail.com 🔮 http://jlaluces.me 📞 (908)414-3555 👂 Los Angeles, California

SUMMARY

Junior Full Stack Web Developer who is ready to create work that has wide-ranging impacts while keeping a fresh mind when learning new technologies. Experience in web development on both front-end and back-end, creating a broad range of applications, discovering new languages and frameworks, and creating sustainable code.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JavaScript, React, Redux, Jest, HTML / CSS, SQL, SQLite, NodeJS, Express, Knex, Python, C, Jest Testing, Enzyme

EXPERIENCE

Lambda Studios · Software Engineer

Sept. 2019 to Feb. 2020 · Remote

- Created various components that interacted with internal APIs as well as external APIs to enhance user's data visualization
- Communicated and clarified clearly with clients by asking thoughtful questions and marking down notes during discussions which resulted in better development cycles
- Utilized agile methodology to evaluate certain functionalities which lead to further optimization throughout the app
- Provided a positive attitude to the rest of the team which helped us bond and lead to a fun, clean development experience
- Constructed a technical design document to outline the major parts of the apps being created

Freelance · Web Developer

Mar. 2019 to Sept. 2019 · Remote

- Followed best practices by using next-gen image formats and properly sizing elements
- Utilized React's component lifecycle methods in order to alter the results given back on the client-side which enhanced the user's experience throughout
- Thoroughly tested the app with audits and Jest / Enzyme testing to provide quality assurance for my clients
- Practiced better communication to clients by giving clear deadlines and addressing issues immediately, resulting in a better experience for the client

Visual Communications · Intern

Oct. 2017 to June 2018 · Los Angeles, California

- Increased exposure to film festivals by reaching out to communities through efficiently advertising and through physical communication.
- Coordinated 2 volunteer teams of 4 people in the setup process of various venues, leading to a visually stunning experience for customers.
- Enhanced company's film festival website by updating and adding 10+ article review posts to the Wordpress website
- Increased profit from film festivals by 5%, creating visually appealing pins by collaborating with the logo designers about the specifications of the logos the company needed
- Taught other interns how to create the products needed at film festivals by writing clear and concise documentation outlining each step

PROJECTS

Let's Get Tacos Feb. 2019 to Mar. 2019

- Researched and convinced all team members that Material-UI should be used to style the application after independently creating a demo showcasing the framework
- Created actions and events to change the Redux store's state
- Refactored 2 backend endpoints with NodeJS and Express as well as added the endpoint to implement the Stripe API feature.
- Used Axios to make API calls that interacted with our NodeJS server in conjunction with Redux's store to trigger asynchronous function calls in our Redux actions

EDUCATION

Lambda School, Certificate in Web Development and Computer Science Mar. 2019

Lambda School is an intensive Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy that focuses on real-world practices, taking students through a hands-on experience using an in-depth curriculum that focuses on Computer Science, Software Engineering, and Web Development.

- Learned and implemented Git branching workflow for large projects.
- Utilized an Agile development workflow during capstone project.
- Created production-ready code using skills in: React, Redux, Node, and Express to create multi-paged applications.